so this morning I woke up and had a
feeling we needed to change the question
but the idea cafe was going to Center on
that is the point of an idea Cafe is
having a meaningful conversation around
a question and the question I had put
out there into the world for the
inaugural cafe was about which teacher
or mentor has had an impact on your life
and this morning when I woke up it be
nine eleven it didn't feel right to have
that conversation not when it's our
first cafe but I wanted to make sure
that it was okay to change the question
so I asked the people who had agreed to
participate and with the understanding
if anyone wasn't ok with it we weren't
gonna change the question but I wanted
to honor the day and someone had said
yeah actually I'm not okay talking about
it but then she had also said that she's
actually not okay talking at all today
because of that so the rest of us
changed the question and talked about
where we were 18 years ago and so these
were people someone in my life who I've
known for a while and but we're not you
know best friends we don't we just
happened to run in the same circles and
run into each other a lot and I love her
I think she's an amazing woman an
amazing mother and I love the work that
she does and then someone who I know
through through Perry girls who I'm just
getting to know she jumped on on to be
to be part of it but I don't know very
much about her besides when the other
person had said no I think I need the
data more and she had like that we
showed she wanted to cancel it all
together she wanted to not have the idea
cafe and she had jumped in and said no
actually I think that this is a positive
way to to do it like if we allow it to
shut down the world and kind of like
they win and so we had it and it was
amazing I will post a link to it it's a
half an hour video spoiler alerts if you
want to actually watch it but I should I
know my story I've known my story for 18
years I was in Australia at the time a
Canadian in Australia and the the
feeling of the world mourning for
America and there was like this eerie
silence and quiet and not even calm
like sadness that was was was in Sydney
the next day on September 12 and because
it happened at night at September 11
there like it'd happen at bedtime and
one of my friends shared that she was in
Greece at the time and she doesn't speak
Greek and it experiencing that that
piece of it that she like what's going
on the third person the person who was
already scheduled to talk and was up for
talking about this he's from and was in
New York at the time and so she shares
her experience there and I was like how
weird that would be and this woman have
this connection that we were both
traveling abroad but she didn't speak
the language and I did speak the
language and yet out of all the people
in the world that could have joined
there was somebody who wasn't even just
in America or just had an inconvenience
on that day it was like right there in
the space that like you don't know
what's going on we all didn't know what
was going on but like right there not
knowing what's going on and how these
moments in history
bring us together and eighteen years
later we can share those stories but
what I want to be able to do is as we
are in history and it's unfolding and be
able to share stories there is and was a
concern about us elevating our voices
above the people who actually were there
and experiencing it and then someone
who's actually there and experienced it
showed up but I do think I don't want to
elevate our voices I think everyone's
story is important and everyone's voice
is important no matter what the topic is
and in normal social media where we are
elevating people and listening to them
on a platform it's very different than
just being part of a conversation part
of a conversation I want to hear
everyone's ideas and everyone's voices
and then who we choose to elevate and
repeatedly listen to should be people
who have a bigger ownership of that
experience in this case miss optimism on
today's idea cafe I would say would take
that one for sure
but the power the power of coming
together and sharing our stories showing
our shared humanity showing that these
moments connect us that our emotions
connect us that we're all human and we
all have something to give is what the
idea Cafe is and it's going to evolve
into its own platform that is designed
for that so anyone no matter what the
experience whether it's a global
experience whether it's a local
experience whether it's a personal
experience whether you're like going
through a divorce you need people to
talk to you about that or you have a
heartbreak or you you know your your
cities having an election or there's bad
weather that that day whatever it is
that that your group wants to talk about
you can talk about that and putting you
together with groups to focus on those
questions so I think today was an
amazing idea cafe and now we have to
brainstorm a question to go for a week -
because I can't follow that up with one
that isn't empowering and enjoyable to
talk about because that is also the
point the point is to have a
conversation with people who are
enjoying being part of that conversation
not a conversation it's going to
something to be palatable to the masses
but it's also a weird medium because
we're having like an intimate
conversation on a very public platform
and owning the awkward weirdness of that
so check it out I will post a link in
the description come over and
participate if you want next Wednesday
at 11 a.m. Pacific Standard Time I don't
yet know what the question is maybe you
could offer me some ideas here about our
world is on its way and it's never felt
closer it's gonna be brought to you by
our diversity our physical or mental our
emotional what makes us different what
makes us the same a better world is on
its way please like and subscribe and
hit that little bell and I'll see you
tomorrow